Guide to the Sighle Kennedy papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VIII: Books Annotated by Sighle Kennedy
  - Three Novels by Samuel Beckett: Molloy, Malone Dies, The Unnamable. New York: Evergreen-Grove Black Cat, 1965. (Box 26)
  - The Unnamable. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1958. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - Waiting for Godot. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1954. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - Watt. New York: Grove and John Calder Ltd.: London, 1959. Two copies. (Box 26)
  - Worstward Ho. New York: Grove, 1983. (Box 26)
  - Beckett, Samuel, et. al. Signature Anthology. London: Calder and Boyars, 1975. (Box 26)
  - Subseries VIII.3: Books about Samuel Beckett
    These are largely scholarly books, many of them classics in the now-enormous field of Beckett studies. Many are paperbacks.
  - Admussen, Richard L. The Samuel Beckett Manuscripts: A Study. Boston: G.K. Hall, 1979. (Box 27)
  - Alvarez, A. Samuel Beckett. New York: Viking, 1973. (Box 27)
  - Bair, Deirdre. Samuel Beckett. New York and London: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1978. (Box 27)
  - Brater, Enoch, ed. Beckett at 80: Beckett in Context. Oxford and New York: Oxford UP, 1986. (Box 27)
  - Busi, Frederick. The Transformations of Godot. Lexington, KY: Kentucky UP, 1980. (Box 27)
  - Cohn, Ruby, ed. Casebook on Waiting for Godot. New York: Grove, 1967. (Box 27)
  - Cohn, Ruby, ed. Samuel Beckett: A Collection of Criticism. New York: McGraw-Hall, 1975. (Box 27)
  - Cohn, Ruby. Samuel Beckett: The Comic Gamut. New Brunswick, NJ: Rutgers UP, 1962. (Box 27)
  - Esslin, Martin. Mediations: Essays on Brecht, Beckett and the Media. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1982. (Box 27)
  - Esslin, Martin. Samuel Beckett: A Collection of Critical Essays. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall, 1965. (Box 27)
  - Fletcher, John and John Spurling. Beckett: A Study of His Plays. New York: Hill and Wang, 1972. (Box 27)
  - Fletcher, John. The Novels of Samuel Beckett. London: Chatto and Windus, 1964. (Box 27)
  - Fletcher, John. Samuel Beckett's Art. London: Chatto and Windus, 1967. (Box 27)
  - Gontarski, S.E. The Intent of Undoing in Sanuel Beckett's Texts. Bloomington, IN: Indiana UP, 1985. (Box 27)
  - Gontarski, S.E., ed. On Beckett: Essays and Criticism. New York: Grove, 1986. (Box 27)
  - Graver, Lawrence and Raymond Federman. Samuel Beckett: The Critical Heritage. London, Henley and Boston: Routledge and Kegan Paul, 1979. (Box 27)
  - Hamilton, Kenneth and Alice Hamilton. Condemned to Life: The World of Samuel Beckett. Grand Rapids, MI: William B. Eerdman's, 1976. (Box 27)
  - Harvey, Lawrence. Samuel Beckett: Poet and Critic. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1970. (Box 27)
  - Karl, Frederick R. A Reader's Guide to the Contemporary English Novel. Revised ed. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1972. (Box 27)
  - Kenner, Hugh. A Reader's Guide to Samuel Beckett. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1973. (Box 27)
  - Kenner, Hugh. Samuel Beckett: A Critical Study. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1961. (Box 27)
  - Kern, Edith. Kierkegaard, Sartre, Beckett. New Haven and London: Yale UP, 1970. (Box 27)
  - Knowlson, James. Light and Darkness in the Theatre of Samuel Beckett. London: Turret, 1972. (Box 27)
  - Knowlson, James. Samuel Beckett: An Exhibition. London: Turret, 1971. (Box 27)
  - Kumar, Shiv K. Bergson and the Stream of Consciousness Novel. New York: NYU Press, 1963. (Box 27)
  - Janvier, Ludovic. Pour Samuel Beckett. Paris: Les Editions de Minuit, 1966. (Box 27)
  - Juliet, Charles. Rencontres avec Bram van Velde. Paris: Fata Morgana, 1978. (Box 27)
  - Mayoux, Jean-Jacques. Samuel Beckett. Essex: Longman, 1974. (Box 27)
  - McMillan, Dougald. Transition 1927-38: The History of a Literary Era. New York: George Braziller, 1976. (Box 27)
  - O'Hara, J.D. Twentieth Century Interpretations of Molloy, Malone Dies, The Unnamable. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice-Hall, 1970. (Box 27)
  - Perloff, Marjorie. The Poetics of Indeterminacy: Rimbaud to Cage. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1980. (Box 27)
  - Pilling, John. Samuel Beckett. London, Henley and Boston: Routledge and Kegan Paul, 1976. (Box 27)
  - Rabinovitz, Rubin. The Development of Samuel Beckett's Fiction. Urbana and Chicago: Illinois UP, 1983. (Box 27)
  - Reid, Alec. All I Can Manage, More than I Could: An Approach to the Plays of Samuel Beckett. Revised ed. New York: Evergreen-Grove, 1971. (Box 27)
  - Scott, Nathan A. Samuel Beckett. New York: Hillary House, 1965. (Box 27)
  - Smith, Joseph H., ed. The World of Samuel Beckett. Baltimore and London: Johns Hopkins UP, 1991. (Box 27)
  - Tindall, William York. Samuel Beckett. Columbia Essays on Modern Writers, no. 4. New York: Columbia UP, 1964. (Box 27)
  - Subseries VIII.4: Books about James Joyce
    This small subseries features scholarly and trade books about Beckett’s friend and mentor, James Joyce.
  - Budgen, Frank. James Joyce and the Makings of Ulysses. Bloomington and London: Indiana UP, 1967. (Box 28)
  - Gilbert, Stuart. James Joyce's Ulysses. 1930. Middlesex: Penguin, 1969. (Box 28)
  - Potts, Willard, ed. Portraits of the Artist in Exile: Recollections of James Joyce by Europeans. San Diego, New York and London: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1986. (Box 28)
  - Power, Arthur. Conversations with James Joyce. Ed. Clive Hart. Chicago: Chicago UP, 1974. (Box 28)
  - Reynolds, Mary T. Joyce and Dante: The Shaping Imagination. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1981. (Box 28)
  - Subseries VIII.5: Translation of Books by Dante
    As with the Beckett books in English, Kennedy seems to have purchased second copies of crucial Dante translations so as to add further marginalia. Featured here are several now-standard English translations of Dante’s writings; most are paperbacks, though also included are a 1904 hardcover edition of D.G. Rossetti’s translation of the Vita Nuova and a 1932 hardcover copy of The Modern Library’s Carlyle-Wicksteed translation of the Commedia. Translations are alphabetized by title and then by translator.
    - Alighieri, Dante. The Divine Comedy. Trans. John Aitken Carlyle, Thomas Okey and Philip H. Wicksteed. New York: Modern Library-Random House, 1932. (Box 29)
    - Inferno.
      - Trans. Allen Mandelbaum. New York: Bantam, 1982. (Box 29)
      - Trans. John D. Sinclair. Revised ed. Oxford and New York: Galaxy-Oxford UP, 1961. (Box 29)
      - Trans. John D. Sinclair. Revised ed. Oxford and New York: Oxford UP, 1961. (Box 29)
      - Trans. Charles S. Singleton. 2 vols. Revised ed. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1977. (Box 29)
    - Paradiso.
      - Trans. Allen Mandelbaum. New York: Bantam, 1986. (Box 29)
      - Trans. John D. Sinclair. Oxford and New York: Galaxy-Oxford UP, 1961. (Box 29)
      - Trans. John D. Sinclair. Oxford and New York: Oxford UP, 1961. (Box 29)
      - Trans. Charles S. Singleton. Revised ed. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1977. (Box 29)
    - Purgatorio.
      - Trans. Henry Wadsworth Longfellow. New York: Dolphin-Doubleday, undated. (Box 29)
      - Trans. Allen Mandelbaum. New York: Bantam, 1984. (Box 29)
      - Trans. John D. Sinclair. Revised ed. Oxford and New York: Galaxy-Oxford UP, 1961. (Box 29)
      - Trans. John D. Sinclair. Revised ed. Oxford and New York: Oxford UP, 1961. (Box 29)
      - Trans. Charles S. Singleton. Revised ed. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1977. (Box 29)
    - Rime. Trans. Patrick S. Diehl. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1979. (Box 29)
    - Vita Nuova.
      - Trans. Mark Musa. Bloomington: Indiana UP, 1973. (Box 29)
      - Dante's New Life. Trans. Dante Gabriel Rossetti. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell, [1904]. (Box 29)
  - Subseries VIII.6: Books about Dante or Related to Kennedy's Dante Project
    Here are scholarly books in English on Dante; also included are bound volumes of Lectura Dantis. An edition of Vico (grouped by Beckett with Dante, Bruno and Joyce in his famous early essay) and the Loeb Classical Library’s Virgil are also present.
    - Barolini, Teodolinda. The Undivine Comedy: Detheologizing Dante. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1992. (Box 29)
    - Bergin, Thomas G. Dante. Riverside Studies in Literature. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1965. (Box 29)
    - Ferrante, Joan M. The Political Vision of the Divine Comedy. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1984. (Box 29)
    - Friederich, Werner P. Dante's Fame Abroad, 1350-1850. Chapel Hill: North Carolina UP, 1950. (Box 29)
    - Gardner, Edmund. Dante and the Mystics. New York: Haskell House, 1968. (Box 29)
    - Harrison, Robert Pogue. The Body of Beatrice. Baltimore and London: Johns Hopkins UP, 1988. (Box 29)
    - Mazzotta, Giuseppe. Dante's Vision and the Circle of Knowledge. Princeton: Princeton UP, 1993. (Box 29)
    - McDougal, Stuart Y. Dante among the Moderns. Chapel Hill and London: North Carolina UP, 1985. (Box 29)
    - Moore, Edward. Studies in Dante. First Series: Scripture and Classical Authors in Dante 1896. New York: Greenwood, 1968. (Box 29)
    - Moore, Edward. Studies in Dante. Third Series: Miscellaneous Essays. 1903. New York: Greenwood, 1968. (Box 29)
    - Toynbee, Paget. Concise Dictionary of Proper Names and Notable Matters in the Works of Dante. New York: Phaeton, 1968. (Box 29)
    - Vittorini, Dominico. The Age of Dante: A Concise History of Italian Culture in the Years of the Early Renaissance. New York: Citadel, 1964. (Box 30)
    - Wicksteed, Philip H. Dante and Aquinas: Being the Substance of the Jowett Lectures of 1911. New York: Haskell House, 1971. (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 6 (Spring 1990). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 6 Supplement: Dante's Divine Comedy: Introductory Readings: I: Inferno (Spring 1990). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 7 (Fall 1990). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 8 (Spring 1991). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 9 (Fall 1991). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 10 (Spring 1992). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 11 (Fall 1992). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 12 Supplement: Dante's Divine Comedy: Introductory Readings II: Purgatorio (Spring 1993). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 12 (Spring 1993). (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 13 (Fall 1993) (Box 30)
    - Lectura Dantis 16-17: Dante's Divine Comedy: Introductory Readings III: Paradiso (Spring-Fall 1995). (Box 30)
  - Vico, Giambattista. On the Study Methods of Our Time. Trans. Elio Gianturco. Indianapolis and New York: Library of Liberal Arts-Bobbs-Merrill, 1965. (Box 30)
  - Virgil. The Aeneid. Trans. Rolfe Humphries. New York: Scribner, 1951. (Box 30)
  - Virgil. Eclogues, Georgics, Aeneid 1-6. Trans. H.R. Fairclough. 1938. Loeb Classical Library. Cambridge, MA: Harvard UP, 1986. (Box 30)
  - Virgil. Aeneid 7-12, The Minor Poems. Trans. H.R. Fairclough. 1934. Loeb Classical Library. Cambridge, MA: Harvard UP, 1986. (Box 30)
  - Subseries VIII.7: Other Books
    This small subseries primarily contains books on ancient Greek and medieval Christian philosophy and literature.
  - The Letters of Abelard and Heloise. Trans. Betty Radice. New York: Penguin, 1974. (Box 30)
  - Aristotle. Ethics. Trans. D.P. Chase. 1911. New York: E.P Dutton and London: J.M. Dent, 1937. (Box 30)
  - Arpino, Giovanni. La suora giovane. Torino: Einaudi, 1959. (Box 30)
  - Auerbach, Erich. Mimesis. Anchor-Doubleday, undated. Damaged. (Box 30)
  - St. Augustine. The City of God. Trans. Marcus Dods. New York: Modern Library-Random House, 1950. (Box 30)
  - St. Augustine. Confessions. Trans. John Pilkington. New York: Liveright, 1943. (Box 30)
  - Boethius. The Consolation of Philosophy. Trans. V.E. Watts. New York: Penguin, 1969. (Box 30)
  - Boethius. Tractates, De Consolatione Philosophiae. Trans. H.Stewart, E.K. Rand, and S.J. Tester. Cambridge MA: Loeb Classical Library-Harvard UP and London: William Heinemann, 1973. (Box 30)
  - Aquinas, St. Thomas. The Philosophy of Saint Thomas Aquinas. Trans. Etienne Gilson and Rev. G.A Erlington. Cambridge: W. Heffer and Sons and St. Louis: B. Herder, 1924. (Box 30)
  - Jonas, Hans. The Gnostic Religion. Second ed. Boston: Beacon, 1958. (Box 30)
  - Kirk, G.S. and J.E. Raven. The Presocratic Philosophers. Cambridge: Cambridge UP, 1966. (Box 30)
  - Levin, Richard. The Question of Socrates. New York and Burlingame: Harcourt-Brace, 1961. (Box 30)
  - De Lorris, Guillaume and Jean de Meur. The Romance of the Rose. Trans. Harry W. Robbins. New York: Meridian-Penguin, 1962. (Box 30)
  - Nilsson, Martin P. A History of Greek Religion. Second ed. New York: W.W. Norton, 1964. (Box 30)
  - West, Rebecca J. Eugenio Montale: Poet on the Edge. Cambridge, MA and London: Harvard UP, 1981. (Box 30)